Julie Simmons

116 Suburban Ave. State College, Pa 16803 Phone: 814-730-9281 Juliesimmons55@gmail.com

Qualifications Summary

Honors graduate with a Master's Degree in Middle/Secondary Instruction and 7-12 teaching certification in Social Studies and Family Consumer Science. Previously, a talented copywriter/editor/manager with over 24 years handling a wide range of responsibilities producing high quality work which contributed to the success of a prominent direct marketing mail order corporation.

Education

Masters of Education, Middle/Secondary InstructionEdinboro University, 2012Bachelor of Arts, HistoryGrove City College, 1984

Certifications

7-12 Social Studies Certification Edinboro University, 2012 **Family Consumer Sciences K-12** Alternative certification 2012

Teacher Professional Development

Bellefonte Area School District 2013 **Promethean Board Training** Bellefonte Area School District 2013 **Vocabulary Strategies** Bellefonte Area School District 2013 **SAS and Student Learning Objectives** Flipping The Classroom State College Area School District 2015 Using Google Sites for Collaboration and Portfolio State College Area School District 2015 **Using Google Classroom and PLC Sharing** State College Area School District 2015 **Google Classroom** State College Area School District 2015 **Suicide Prevention** State College Area School District 2015 **Quick Formative Assessments** State College Area School District 2016

Professional Preparation

Teaching Practicum: Eisenhower Middle/High School, Russell, Pa. Designed and taught lessons in World Geography, World History, Ancient Civilizations, American Government and Sociology.

Student Teaching:

Developed lessons plans incorporating diverse student-centered learning strategies to align with state standards, designed a variety of assessments to gauge students' learning, displayed students' work, videotaped class presentation, maintained digital grade book. Attended professional development seminars and faculty meetings.

Student Teacher: American History, Psychology January 2012 – March 2012

Supervisor: Mr. Todd Heffern

October 2012-December 2012

Eisenhower Middle/High School, Russell, Pa.

Student Teacher: Pennsylvania History, American History March 2012-May 2012

Supervisor: Mrs. Stacey Robinault

Youngsville Elementary/Middle School, Youngsville, Pa.

Teaching Experience

Learning Support Paraprofessional State College School DistrictJanuary 2016 - presentPredictable Long Term Sub State College School District (FCS)September 2015- January 2016ESL Writing/English Teacher Grier School, Tyrone, PaSummers 2014, 2015Substitute Teacher State College School District, State College, PaSeptember 2012 - June 2015Substitute Teacher Bellefonte, Penns Valley School DistrictsSeptember 2012-June 2013Substitute Teacher Boulder Valley School District, Boulder, ColoradoSeptember 2014- May 2015Substitute Teacher Warren County School District, Warren, PaSeptember 2010-June 2011

Experience Working with Children

- Sunday school and Confirmation class teacher
- Christian Education teacher: middle school students
- Instructor: youth exercise classes and swim lessons at Warren County YMCA
- Coach: girls and boys recreational soccer

Professional Experience

Blair LLC, Warren, Pa 16366

1986-2010

Women's Copy Manager. Wrote, designed and edited advertisements and customer correspondence, managed work flow, trained and supervised employees, attended photo shoots, worked with merchants in developing advertisement campaigns, gave presentations to fellow employees, customer focus groups and corporate managers.

References:

Mrs. Christina Manning Assistant Principal, 11th Grade Administrator, State College School District cmm50@scasd.org 814-272-1839

Mrs. Mary Peterson Family Consumer Science Teacher, State College School District mkp12@scasd.org 814-441-9879

Mr. Francois Lambert Modern Languages Department Chair/Director of Summer TOEFL and SAT Program, Grier School flambert@grier.org
814-684-3000